Guide to the Bobbye S. Ortiz Papers, 1919-1993 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files Series, 1938-[198-] and undated (bulk, 1960-1984)
  - General Files Subseries, [196-]-[198-] and undated
    - Echoes: Justice, Peace and Creation News (Box 22)
    - Feminism and Socialism (Box 22)
    - Feminist Educational Materials (Box 23)
    - Feminist Women's Health Centers (Box 23)
    - French Feminism -- Newspapers, 1970s (Box 23)
    - Gurky, John, excerpts from Challenges to Capitalism (Box 23)
    - Health and Women (Box 23)
    - Hemlock Society (Box 23)
    - Humor (Box 23)
    - International Feminism (Box 23)
    - International Women's Day, 1984 -- Magazine (Box 23)
    - Italian Feminist Periodicals, 1970s (one item oversize) (Box 23)
    - Victor Jara (Box 23)
    - Labor (Box 23)
    - Liberator (Box 23)
    - Listen Real Loud: News of Women's Liberation Worldwide (American Friends Service Committee) (Box 23)
    - Magazines -- Women (Box 23)
    - Many Sisters: Women in Cross-Cultural Perspective (Box 23)
    - Marxism Today (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Monthly Review (Box 24)
    - Monthly Review -- History as it Happened (Box 24)
    - Monthly Review -- Prisoner Book Program (Box 24)
    - Monthly Review -- Publications (Box 24)
    - Las mujeres del Cono Sur escriben (Box 24)
    - Music (Box 24)
    - NACLA -- George Black Article and Response (Box 24)
    - New York Circus Publications, Center for Social Justice and International Awareness (Box 24)
    - Newspapers (misc.) (Box 24)
    - Ocean Hill / Brownsville School Controversy (Box 24)
    - Off Our Backs (Box 24)
    - Paris -- 1968 -- Bound Publications (Box 24)
    - Paris -- 1968 -- Documents (Box 24)
    - Paris -- 1968 -- Miscellaneous (Box 24)
    - Paris -- 1968 -- Newspapers (Box 25)
    - Paris -- 1968 -- Periodicals, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Linus Pauling Institute Newsletter (Box 25)
    - Poetry (Box 25)
    - Poetry -- Raul Rivero (Box 25)
    - Poetry -- Women -- National and International (Box 25)
    - Quotes (Box 25)
    - Ramapo College Master Lecture Series on Religion and Social Change -- Proposal (Box 25)
    - Ramparts (Box 25)
    - Realidad Agraria (Box 25)
    - Research Notecards -- Women (Box 25)
    - Socialist Feminism (Box 25)
    - Spectator, University of Indiana (Box 25)
    - Translations (Box 25)
    - Vanidades (Box 25)
    - Ana Vasquez (Box 25)
    - Violence Against Women -- Publications (Box 25)
    - WUS News, World University Service Publication (Box 25)
    - WIRE (Box 25)
    - WIRE -- "La Condicin de la Mujer en Mexico" (Box 25)
    - Wiser Links: Newsletter of the Women's International Resource Centre (Box 26)
    - Women and the International Division of Labor (Box 26)
    - Women and Liberation Theology (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Articles, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Book Lists (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Mara Candelaria Navas (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Newsletters (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Newspapers (Box 26)
    - Women's Liberation Movement -- Nichols, Margaret -- Lesbian Sex Therapy Articles (Box 26)
    - Women's Studies Book Lists, Reviews (Box 26)
- Photographs and Slides Series, [192-?]-[ca. 1989] and undated
  Begins with snapshots taken in Europe and Mexico which are CLOSED to research. These are followed by very fine 8x10 portraits of indigenous people identified as Mexican Lacandon, taken by well-known activist Gertrude Duby Blom. Another folder contains casual snapshots by Gail Lerner Saharoui, mostly portraying unidentified people, chiefly women performing various jobs such as weaving; these were possibly taken in India or the Middle East. There are many images documenting Ortiz's trips to China (1974) and Latin America (ca. 1984) in the form of photographs and slides. This series ends with photo negatives of an International Women's Day March in 1978.
  [This series is partially CLOSED until 2050. A few photographs in the first box are closed to research. Contact Research Services.]
  - Photos -- [192-]-[197-] (Box 27)
  - Photos -- 1953-1979 and undated (Box 27)
  - Photos -- 1943-1969 and undated (additional photo removed to Oversize Series) (Box 27)
  - Panoramic photograph in which Louis Suckle, Bobbye Ortiz' father, can be seen, [192-?] [Second row: immediately behind 14th man from left, front row. The front row begins with seated man and ends with cross-legged man.] (Stored in OVSZ Cab. V:5) (Box 27)
  - Photos by Gertrude Duby Blom, 6 black and white 8x10 photographs, undated (Box 27)
    ( Mexican Lacandon tribe photographic portraits, [. 193-])
  - Photos by Gail Lerner Saharoui, 8 color snapshots, unidentified country, 1985 and undated (Box 27)
  - Photos -- Nicaragua, [ca. 1984] (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Latin America (Box 27)
  - Slides -- China -- Cities, Unidentified (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Nanking (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Wu Shih (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Sun Yat Sen Medical College / East is Red Kindergarten / Canton Dali Commune / Misc. Canton (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Shanghai (Box 27)
  - Slides -- Cadre School / Misc. Beijing (Box 27)
  - Photos -- 6 black and white 8x10 unidentified prints, possibly from Latin America: groups of people, interior of dairy [?], undated (Box 27)
  - Photos (negatives) -- Viki Ortiz (VO) -- International Women's Day March, 1978 (Box 27)
  - Unidentified Matted Photos (stored in oversize) (Box 27)
  - Photocopy of News Photo -- Camilo Ortiz ca. 1982 (Box 27)
- Cultural Artifacts Series, [196-]-[198-] and undated
  Buttons, T-shirts, and poster-size broadsides connected to various events or issues in countries around the world. Some items have been removed to the Oversize Series.
  - Buttons (Box 28)
    - Latin America / U.S. Imperialism (Box 28)
    - Women's Liberation (Box 28)
    - AIDS (Box 28)
    - Parenting / Children (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. Social Movements (Box 28)
  - T-Shirts (VO), 16 folders (Box 28, 29)
    - International Women's Liberation (Box 28, 29)
    - Latin America / U.S. Imperialism (Box 28, 29)
    - Lesbian and Gay Rights (Box 28, 29)
    - AIDS (Box 28, 29)
  - Posters (stored in oversize cabinet) (Oversize-folder OC:V:5)
    - Africa and Middle East, 1 folder (Oversize-folder OC:V:5)
    - Europe (France and Italy), 1 folder (Oversize-folder OC:V:5)
    - Art Museum Posters (France), 1 folder (Oversize-folder OC:V:5)
    - One poster from student/worker strikes in France, [1968?] (Oversize-folder OC:V:5)
  - Posters (stored in oversize cabinet) (Oversize-folder OC:V:7)
    - U.S. Movements (e.g., Black Panthers, Socialist/Marxists, Women's Liberation, Anti-War), 2 folders (Oversize-folder OC:V:7)
    - Latin America, 4 folders (Oversize-folder OC:V:7)
    - International Women's Day (various countries), 1 folder (Oversize-folder OC:V:7)
  - Original art work done for Bobbye and Viki, 1 folder (Oversize-folder OC:V:7)
- Audio Recordings Series
  - China Tape 1: Sun Yat Sen Medical College, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0062)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 2: Sun Yat Sen Medical College / East is Red Kindergarten, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0063)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 3: East is Red Kindergarten / Shanghai Industrial Exhibit, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0064)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 4: Shanghai Industrial Exhibit / Shanghai #3 Machine Tool Plant, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0065)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 5: China Shakes the World / Pei Kuang Middle School, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0066)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 6: Pei Kuang Middle School / Comrade Wu / Children's Palace, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0067)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 7: Children's Palace / Fung Chen Workers, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0068)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 8: Fung Chen Workers / Women's Discussion, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0069)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 9: Women's Discussion / Shanghai Harbor #5 / Wu Shih, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0070)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 10: Wu-Shih, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0071)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 11: Wu-Shih / Tai Lake / Hura Commune, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0072)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 12: Hura Commune / Clay Fig. Factory Wu-Shih / Nanking Bridge, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0073)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 13: Nanking Bridge / Barefoot Dr. Hura Commune / Nanking Primary School / Kids' Performance, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0074)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 14: Nanking Middle School, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0075)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 15: Nanking Middle School, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0076)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 16: Nanking Chemical Fiber Plant / City Planning Committee (damaged), undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0077)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 17: Nanking City Planning Committee, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0078)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 18: Nanking City Planning Committee, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0079)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 19: Dali Commune, Canton, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0080)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 20: Feng Shen Comm, Beijing, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0081)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 21: Feng Shen Comm. / Beijing University, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0082)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 22: Beijing University / Burchett to Baker, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0083)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 23: Burchett to Baker / Cadre School, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0084)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 23.5: Burchett to Baker / Cadre School, 1973-06-29
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0085)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 24: Cadre School, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0086)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 25: Beijing University Cultural Revolution Education, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0087)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 26: Beijing University Legal System, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0088)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 27: unidentified, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0089)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - China Tape 28: Canton PLA Song and Dance Co., undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0090)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 1: Luis Alberto Franco Corts, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0091)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 2: Encuentro de Mujeres, March 1985, 1985-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0092)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 3: Encuentro de Mujeres, March 1985, 1985-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0093)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 4: Encuentro de Mujeres, March 1985, 1985-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0094)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 5: Encuentro de Mujeres, March 1985, 1985-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0095)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 6: AMNLAE, 1984-10-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0096)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 7: AMNLAE / Cuidad Sandido, 1984-10-03
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0097)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 8: Jacqueline Cuevas, Centro Antonio Valdivieso, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0098)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 9: Marina Esther Torres, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0099)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 10: Hilda Bolt, FSLN, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0100)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 11: Aida Redondo and Daniel del Solar, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 32, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0101)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 30)
  - Nicaragua Tape 12: AMES Costa Rica, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0002)
    - WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00978-SET-0001, Object RL00978-CS-0002.WAV)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 1: "Angela", undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0004)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 2: Playa Girn, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0005)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 3: Isla de la Juventad / Fed. of Cuban Women, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0006)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 4: Isla de la Juventad / China Shakes the World, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0007)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 5: Cuidad Sandido and Pinar del Rio, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0008)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 6: Musical Chorus / Cuba -- Musical Heritage, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0009)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 7: Cuba Sings for Angela Davis, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0010)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 8: Fidel Castro, 1968-01-02
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0011)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 9: Fidel Castro, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0012)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 10: Fidel Castro, 1969-01-02
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0013)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Cuba Tape 11: The Four Fishermen / Fidel Castro, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0014)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 1: Latin American Music / AFWIC, 1979
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0015)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 2: WBAI Radio Show, Bobbye Ortiz, narrator, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0016)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 3: Laura Allende, 1976-12-10
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0017)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 4: WBAI interview with "Amanda", undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0018)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 5: WBAI interview with "Amanda", undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0019)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 6: AFWIC with Maria Elena Carrera, 1977-05-06
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0020)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 7: AFWIC with Maria Elena Carrera, 1977-05-06
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0021)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 8: Relatives of Desaparecidos, 1979
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0022)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 9: Hayde Alarcon, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0023)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Chile Tape 10: Mark Cooper, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0024)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 1: Bettina Aptheker, feminist, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0025)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 2: Bettina Aptheker, feminist, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0026)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 3: Bettina Aptheker, feminist, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0027)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 4: Juliet Mitchell, feminist, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0028)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 5: Labor on the Line, 1985-10-30
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0029)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 6: Angela Fernandez, Dominican writer, 1987-11-11
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0030)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 7: Project Crossfire, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0031)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 8: WIRE: Women's Poetry in the Third World, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0032)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 9: Interview with Bobbye Ortiz, 1981-09-25
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0001)
    - WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00978-SET-0001, Object RL00978-CS-0001.WAV)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 10: Children's Letter, 1981
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0033)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - United States and other Tape 11: Interview with David A. Siqueiros (Mexican graphic artist and political activist), undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette missing)
    - Audiocassette use copy (Box 31)
  - Guitarra Armada, ENIGRAC Records CE-003, 1979
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0034)
    - WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00978-SET-0001, Object RL00978-CS-0034.WAV)
  - Nicaragua: Darkness into Light, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0035)
  - Carlos Mejia Godoy; Nicaragua Libre, tape 1, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0036)
  - Carlos Mejia Godoy; Nicaragua Libre, tape 2, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0037)
  - Musica feminista Nicaragua, 1985, 1985-03-08
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0003)
    - WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00978-SET-0001, Object RL00978-CS-0003.WAV)
  - Carlos Puebla: Che Guevara, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0038)
  - Virulo: La Historia de Cuba, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0039)
  - Chile: 10 Years of Cultural Resistance (excerpts from 1st National Congress of Artists and Cultural Workers of Chile, Santiago, 1983), 1984
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0040)
  - Catalunya amb la luga dels drets dels pobles. Homenage a Pablo Neruda, 1977-05
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0041)
  - Gabriela Mistral: a 25 aos de su muerte, 1982
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0042)
  - Sueno Americano, 1982
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0043)
  - Brazilian Protest Music, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0044)
  - Banda Tepejani: Music from the Revolutionary Struggle in El Salvador, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0045)
  - El Salvador: El pueblo vencer, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0046)
  - El Salvador: Its People, Its Struggle, Its Songs, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0047)
  - Ali Primera: Adis en dolor mayor, dedicato alla resistenza cilena (Italy), 1975
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0048)
  - Harp: Holly Near, Arlo Guthrie, Ronnie Gilbert, Pete Seeger, 1984
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0049)
  - Lucha Means "Struggle", 1977
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0050)
  - Song and Struggle: Women in the Americas, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0051)
  - San Francisco Mime Troupe: Steeltown, 1984
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0052)
  - Anna Casalino: Sebben che siamo donne (Italy), 1982
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0053)
  - Canzoniere delle lame: Scarpe nuove eppur bisogna andare, 1980
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0054)
  - Amore e potere: Il canzoniere femminista (Italy), 1977
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0055)
  - Guatemala Menshu, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0056)
  - Susana Rinaldi, Dale Nomas, [Brazilian protest music?], undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0057)
  - Gruppe Chuzp, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0058)
  - Third World Women's Voices, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0059)
  - Bread and Raises: Songs for Working Women Sung by Bobbie McGee, 1981
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0060)
  - Seder Melodies, undated
    - Original audiocassette (Box 34, Audio-cassette RL00978-CS-0061)
- Index Card Catalog Series, undated
  Two shoebox-size containers hold hundreds of index cards representing Bobbye Ortiz's personal library. Organized by subject, in original order. Box 36 also contains three unidentified reels of sound recordings. These are closed to research: use copies must be made.
  - Monthly Review Publications (Box 35-36)
  - Women (Box 35-36)
  - Marxism/ Socialism (Box 35-36)
  - Literature (Box 35-36)
  - Central America (Box 35-36)
  - Latin America (Box 35-36)